<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<world>
	<continent name="Asia">
		<country name="Afghanistan" capital="Kabul" flag="afganB">
			<flagMeaning>Afghanistan has often changed its flag (especially during the last century), due to the fact that the country is very often at war (civil or against foreign countries). The flag shown here was adopted on January 27th 2002, and is based on the Afghan flag from the 1970s. The colours of the flag are interpreted as standing for progress from the dark times of the past sacrifices to prosperity. The colours have the following meaning: black for the past flags, red for heroes' blood spilled in the fight for independence, and green is for the Islamic faith, and for hope in the future. According to William Crampton, the coat of arms is based on previous pre-Communist models and contains a representation of a mosque within a wreath of wheat-ears. Above the wreath is the "Shahada", the Moslem confession of faith, with - in very small letters - the slogan "Allahu Aqbar" (God is Great).</flagMeaning>
			<history>Afghanistan's recent history is characterised by war and civil unrest. After being under British control at the turn of the century followed by an unstable monarchy, Afghanistan became a republic in 1973. In 1978 the communists took control, and the Soviet Union invaded the following year,leading to a 10-year-long war. After the communists' collapse in 1992, Afghanistan fell into the hands of rivalling warlords, and eventually came under the control of the Islamist group, the Taliban. Following the September 11th attacks in 2001, the United States invaded Afghanistan and overthrew the Taliban, installing a transitional government. Afghanistan still continues to suffer from unrest and poverty, although a concerted international aid effort is under way to help repair the country.</history>
			<historyClue>Following the September 11th attacks in 2001, the United States invaded this country and overthrew the Taliban, installing a transitional government.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Iran</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="India" capital="New Delhi" flag="indiaB">
			<flagMeaning>There is a multitude of different explanations for the colours of the Indian flag. Here only two are given. The first is the simplest: the saffron (orange) represents the Hindus; the green the Muslims; and the white the peace between them. The blue well is the Gandhian spinning wheel. The second explanation describes the blue wheel as being the "Dharma Chakra" - the wheel of law. The chakra is a symbol dating from the second century BC. The symbol of the wheel is intended to represent life in movement and death in stagnation. The saffron (orange) stands for courage and sacrifice; the white for purity and truth; and the green for growth and success (most likely of the land and life itself).</flagMeaning>
			<history>India is part of the Asian continent. The Indian civilisation goes back at least 50,000 years. India was colonised by Great Britain in the nineteenth century. India's ninety-year fight for independence is said to to have begun with the "Sepoy (soldier) Mutiny" (or India's "first war of independence") in 1857 with the non-violent resistance movement, led by Gandhi and Nehru, finally resulting in India's independence in 1947.</history>
			<historyClue>This country was colonised by Great Britain in the nineteenth century, but in 1857 its ninety-year fight for independence is said to to have begun with the "Sepoy (soldier) Mutiny" with the non-violent resistance movement.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Nepal</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Mongolia" capital="Ulaanbaatar" flag="mongoliaB">
			<flagMeaning>The red stands for revolution and the blue represents the sky. The golden symbol on the left hand side is rich in meaning; the symbol itself is called Soyombo, it is the national emblem of Mongolia. The fire at the top symbolises revival and growth, and also the family hearth and the continuity of the people. The fire has three tongues of flame, symbolising past, present, and future. Below the fire are symbols of the sun and moon, links to the pre-Buddhist nature religion of the Mongols. In ancient Mongolian symbolism, an arrow or spear pointing to the ground meant death. In the Soyombo, two downward-pointing triangles signify death to the enemies of the Mongols. Two horizontal rectangles represent honesty and fairness between rulers and the people. Set between the two horizontal rectangles is the Chinese sign of yin and yang, representing dark and light, female and male, hot and cold - the unity of all opposites in the cosmos. In Mongolian symbolism, the figures in the yin-yang circle represent two fish denoting reason and wisdom because fish never close their eyes. The two vertical rectangles represent a fortress, recalling the old Mongolian proverb "The friendship of two men is stronger than stone walls"; the fortress signifies that the unity of the Mongol people is the foundation of the nation's strength.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Mongolia is part of the Asian continent. Mongolia is famous for its (past) commander Gengis Khan who, during the 13th century, conquered a huge Eurasian empire. After his death the empire was divided into several powerful Mongol states, but these broke apart in the 14th century. The Mongols eventually retired to their original grassy, treeless homelands and came under Chinese rule. Mongolia won its independence in 1921 with Soviet backing. A Communist regime was installed in 1924.</history>
			<historyClue>This country is famous for its (past) commander Gengis Khan.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Russia</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Pakistan" capital="Islamabad" flag="pakistanB">
			<flagMeaning>The white represents minorities; the dark green field represents Muslim majority; the crescent on the flag represents progress; the five-rayed star represents light and knowledge.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Pakistan is part of the Asian continent. While Pakistan as a country is relatively new, the Indus River region is known as a cradle of civilization. Archaeologists have found fossils of homo sapiens in the area which date back 50,000 years. Early in the 16th century, Pakistan became part of the Mughal Empire. By the early 19th century, the Sikhs had consolidated their power and declared Lahore their capital. Within a few decades, however, the Sikhs were defeated in battle by the English, and Pakistan became part of the British Raj. When India prepared for independence from the British in the 1940s, Muslim Indians pushed for their own independent state, and the republic of Pakistan came into being on August 14, 1947 as a Muslim homeland.</history>
			<historyClue>The Sikhs were defeated in battle by the English in the mid 19th century, and this country became part of the British Raj. On August 14, 1947, having been granted independence, it came into being as a Muslim homeland.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Afghanistan</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Bangladesh" capital="Dhaka" flag="banglaB">
			<flagMeaning>The red sun denotes freedom and the blood shed to achieve independence; the background colour symbolises the greenery of Bangladesh with its vitality and youthfulness. Many Bangladesh authors insist on the fact that the green colour is not linked with the Islamic green colour and that too often, people are interpreting wrongfully the Bangladesh flag.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Bangladesh is part of the Asian continent. It came into existence in 1971 when Bengali East Pakistan withdrew formally from its union with West Pakistan. The "independent, sovereign republic of Bangladesh" was first proclaimed in a radio message broadcast from a captured station in Chittagong on March 26, 1971. On April 17, the "Mujibnagar" government formally proclaimed independence and named Mujib as its president. Mujib was the then leader of East Pakistan's dominant party, and as such was demanding autonomy from the arbitrary and feudal interests of West Pakistan. Mujib was captured by the Pakistan army and incarcerated in West Pakistan on 25 March 1971 during the campaign by the Pakistan army to terrorise East Pakistan into submission and was in jail on 26 March when independence was proclaimed. On December 6 1971, India became the first nation to recognize the new Bangladeshi government.</history>
			<historyClue>This country came into existence in 1971 when Bengali East Pakistan withdrew formally from its union with West Pakistan.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>India</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="China" capital="Beijing" flag="chinaB">
			<flagMeaning>The red colour is said to symbolise revolution; the big yellow star the C.C.P.(Chinese Communist Party) and the 4 smaller yellow stars (pointing at the bigger star) - according to the Chinese government - the "great unity of the Chinese people under the guidance of the C.C.P</flagMeaning>
			<history>China belongs to the Asian continent. The Chinese nation is the longest existing continuous nation in human history. In the eyes of the world, China is synonymous with the terra-cotta army of third century BC, the Great Wall, the Silk Road, the last emperor and the Forbidden City. The first prehistoric dynasty is said to be the Xia dynasty, from about the twenty-first to the sixteenth century B.C. The start of recorded history acknowledged by the academic commences with the Shang Dynasty (1765 BC - 1122 BC) as a result of the discovery of oracle bones (tortoise shells and flat cattle bones with inscribed characters of ancient Chinese). China's civilisation is dated later than the Sumer Civilisation of 3500 BC, Ancient Egypt of 3100 BC, Minoan of 2000 BC, and Indian of 2500 BC. Excavations, however, have produced refined potteries going back as much as 5000 BC.  The last of the dynasties (Manchu Qing) dates from 1644 to as late as 1911. Originally one of the world's leading civilisations in the arts and in sciences, by the end of the 19th century China was facing famine, war, defeat and occupation. In August 1912 a new political, nationalist party was founded by Song Jiaoren. The decade of 1928-37 was one of consolidation and accomplishment by the Guomindang. After World War II, the communist leader Mao Zedong (aka Mao Tse Tung) established a dictatorship that undermined the Nationalist government and cost 10 million people their lives. On October 1, 1949, the People's Republic of China was formally established, with its national capital at Beijing. "The Chinese people have stood up!" declared Mao as he announced the creation of a "people's democratic dictatorship." After Mao's death in 1976 and a two-year power struggle, Deng Xiaoping became China's paramount leader gradually introducing economic reforms favoring the exportation with other countries and mending the 30-year rift with the USSR, while keeping a strong political control until ill health forced him to resign in 1994.</history>
			<historyClue>This nation is the longest existing continuous nation in human history, and in the eyes of the world, is synonymous with the terra-cotta army of third century BC.
</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Mongolia</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Israel" capital="Jerusalem" flag="israB">
			<flagMeaning>The blue stripes on the Israelite flag were inspired by the stripes on the tallit (a traditional prayer scarf used by Jewish people). Many symbolic meanings were attributed to the blue colour. Rabbi Meir said that it "recalls the colour of the sky"; Rabbi Judah ben Illai maintained that the colour of Aaron's staff (Aaron is a character from the bible) was light blue, as were the Tablets of the Law (also known as the 10 commandments), and this is why God commanded the Jews to include it on their tallits - to remind them to follow the 10 commandments". The six-pointed star made of two triangles appeared - according to Jewish tradition - on the shield of King David (from the bible) so it is referred as the "Shield of David". The same symbol appeared on King Solomon's (another biblical character) ring and, therefore, it is also known as the Seal of Solomon. This symbol is considered to be a magical protection against evil.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Israel is located on the Asian continent. The people of Israel (also called the "Jewish People") trace their origin to Abraham, the creator of the universe (see Old Testament). Abraham, his son Yitshak (Isaac), and grandson Jacob (Israel), are referred to as the patriarchs of the Israelites. The rule of Israelites in the land of Israel starts with the conquests of Joshua (c.1250 BC). The period from 1000-587 BC is known as the "Period of the Kings". The most noteworthy kings were King David (1010-970 BC), who made Jerusalem the Capital of Israel, and his son Solomon (Shlomo, 970-931 BC), who built the first temple in Jerusalem as prescribed in the Tanach (Old Testament). In 587 BC, Babylonian Nebuchadnezzar's army captured Jerusalem, destroyed the temple, and exiled the Jews to Babylon (modern day Iraq). The year 587 BC marks a turning point in the history of the region. From this year onwards, the region was ruled or controlled by a succession of superpower empires of the time. After World War II,in 1948, Jewish Community in Israel under the leadership of David Ben-Gurion reestablished sovereignty over their ancient homeland. Declaration of independence of the modern State of Israel was announced on the day that the last British forces left Israel (May 14, 1948). The United Nation partitioned the area into Arab and Jewish states. The Arabs rejected the arrangement and inevitably war was declared. A day after the declaration of independence of the State of Israel, armies of five Arab countries, Egypt, Syria, Transjordan, Lebanon and Iraq, invaded Israel. Arab states have jointly waged four full scale wars against Israel: 1948 War of Independence, 1956 Sinai War, 1967 Six Day War and 1973 Yom Kippur War. Despite many peace treaties signed by the two parties, Israel and its Arab neighbours - Jordan, Lebanon, Syria and Egypt - have been experiencing violent fights and deep tensions for the last 50 years.</history>
			<historyClue>The United Nation partitioned the area into Arab and Jewish states. The Arabs rejected the arrangement and inevitably war was declared. The day after the declaration of independence, armies of five Arab countries, Egypt, Syria, Transjordan, Lebanon and Iraq, invaded.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Egypt</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Japan" capital="Tokyo" flag="japanB">
			<flagMeaning>The national flag is called "Hinomaru" meaning "sun disc". It is often confused with the Japanese military flag that has sun rays all around it. The symbolic meaning of the national flag is simple: a red sun over a white field.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Japan is part of the Asian continent. It is generally believed that Japan was founded in 660 BC, with the first emperor, Jimmu. During the Yayoi Period (300 BC to 300 AD), the rice culture was imported into Japan around 100 BC. With the introduction of agriculture, social classes started to evolve, and parts of the country began to unite under powerful land owners. By the beginning of the Kofun Period (300 - 538), a center of power had developed in the fertile Kinai plain, and by about 400 AD the country was united as Yamato Japan with its political center in and around the province of Yamato. The period's name comes from the large tombs (kofun) that were built for the political leaders of that era. In the year 538 or 552 Buddhism was introduced to Japan. In 645, Nakatomi no Kamatari started the era of the Fujiwara clan that was to last until the rise of the military class (samurai) in the 11th century. In the same year, a new government and administrative system was established - all land was bought by the state and redistributed equally among the farmers in a large land reform in order to introduce the new tax system. Japan's history is then broken into periods named after the ruling emperor, up until 1947 when a new constitution went into effect dictating that the emperor had no political and military power, but was merely the figurehead for the state.  Japan played a very minor part in WWI but fought against the Allies during World War II. On July 27, 1945, the Allied powers requested Japan in the Potsdam Declaration to surrender unconditionally, or destruction would continue. However, the military would not think of surrendering under such terms, even after US military forces dropped two atomic bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki on August 6 and 9, and the Soviet Union entered the war against Japan on August 8. On August 14, however, the emperor Showa finally decided to surrender unconditionally. After World War II had ended, Japan was devastated. All the large cities (with the exception of Kyoto), the industries and the transportation networks were severely damaged. A severe shortage of food continued for several years. After the Korean War, and accelerated by it, the recovery of Japan's economy flourished. The economic growth resulted in a quick rise of the living standards, changes in society and one of the strongest economies in the world with  its main exports being cars, electronic devices and computers.</history>
			<historyClue>The military refused to think of surrendering unconditionally, even after US military forces dropped two atomic bombs on August 6 and 9, and the Soviet Union entered the war against this country on August 8, 1945.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>this chain of islands has the North Pacific Ocean on the East.</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Thailand" capital="Bangkok" flag="thaiB">
			<flagMeaning>The central blue stripe represents the monarchy, the two white stripes the Theravada Buddhist religion (Theravada Buddhists were monks who practised medicine and helped travellers), and the outer red stripes the land or the nation.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Thailand is located on the Asian country. The first true Thai kingdom was established in AD 1238, though the country had been settled since 3,600 BC. The subsequent two centuries are known as the Sukhothai period, a kind of Golden Age when Thais made great contributions to writing and Theravada Buddhism creating an empire which eventually fell into decline. Although it was occasionally dominated for periods by its Southeast Asian neighbors, Thailand (or Siam, as it was called then) was the only country in the region not colonised by Europeans. Modern Thai history begins with the revolution of 1932, which shifted power from the king to a coalition of military and elected officials. In 1939, the country changed its name from Siam to Thailand. Despite its loss of power, the monarchy continues to exert enormous influence on Thai people. The near-unanimous approval of the monarchy has lent a stability to Thailand not found in some other Southeast Asian countries.</history>
			<historyClue>Although it was occasionally dominated for periods by its Southeast Asian neighbors, Siam, as it was called then, was the only country in the region not colonised by Europeans.
</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Burma</geoClue>
		</country>
	</continent>
	<continent name="Europe">
		<country name="Austria" capital="Vienna" flag="austriaB">
			<flagMeaning>There is a legend behind the origin of the Austrian flag. An early Austrian ruler (supposedly Duke Leopold V) wore a white tunic in battle (supposedly the Battle of Ptolemais in 1191). Apparently the battle was so bloody that the ruler's whole tunic was covered in blood. When he took of his belt, the part of the tunic that was protected by the belt was still white. Even if the experts can not be sure about the exactitude of the names and places, they agree that this legend is the origin of the Austrian flag.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Austria is part of the European continent. Austrian history is believed to have pre-dated the Habsburg Dynasty with Celts, Romans and Germans occupying and developing the Alpine-Danubian region from around 400 BC until around 493 which saw the end of the Roman era. The following eras would see various germanic and slavic tribes vying and winning control of this region. The Duchy of Austria was just one of the duchies and lands that the Habsburgs eventually acquired in the eastern Alpine-Danubian region, until the fourteenth century when the Luxemburg dynasty then residing in Prague eventually acquired it. The Habsburgs became known as the House of Austria after the Swiss peasantry ousted them from their original family seat in Habichtsburg in the Swiss canton of Aargau in 1386. The name Austria subsequently became an informal way to refer to all the lands possessed by the House of Austria, even though it also remained the proper, formal name of a specific region. Thus, through the legacy of common rule by the House of Austria, the lands that constitute the modern state of Austria indirectly adopted the name of one region of the country as the formal national name in the early twentieth century. Austrias security and prosperity during the second half of the twentieth century are a striking contrast to the instability and poverty of the first half of the century. Between 1914 and 1950, Austrians had five different forms of government and four different currencies. After enduring much hardship during World War I, they experienced the collapse of Austria-Hungary (also seen as the Austro-Hungarian Empire) and the proclamation of the Republic of Austria. In the early 1920s, they endured hyperinflation and in the 1930s the Great Depression. The end of Austria's fledgling democracy and the establishment of an authoritarian regime in 1934 was followed by the demise of Austria altogether when Nazi Germany occupied the country in 1938. The proclamation of the Second Republic in 1945 began a long period of peace and prosperity. However, the republic's first years were a difficult time of economic and social reconstruction that occurred while Austria was occupied by the Four Powers (Britain, France, the Soviet Union, and the United States). War, inflation, unemployment, poverty, authoritarian and totalitarian rule, and foreign occupation formed the average Austrian's experience during the first half of the twentieth century. By 1955 Austria had regained its independence, laid the foundations for decades of sustained economic growth, and established a system of cooperation among rival political parties, interest groups, and government bodies that brought the country an unprecedented degree of stability. In 1995, Austria became a member of the European Economic Community (now EU).</history>
			<historyClue>Between 1914 and 1950, this country went through five different forms of government and four different currencies. The end of this country's fledgling democracy and the establishment of an authoritarian regime in 1934 were followed by its demise altogether when Nazi Germany occupied the country in 1938.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Italy</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Belarus" capital="Minsk" flag="belarusB">
			<flagMeaning>Red symbolises Belarus' glorious past. Red was the colour of the victorious standards of the Belarusian regiments that defeated crusaders at Grunewald; and was the colour of the battle flags of the Red Army divisions and Belarusian guerrilla detachments that liberated the country from fascist invaders and their henchmen. Green symbolises the future. It is the colour of hope, spring and revival; the colour of forests and fields. The Belarusian decorative pattern symbolizes Belarus' rich cultural heritage, its spiritual continuity, and the unity of its people.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Belarus is located in Europe, on the North of Ukrainia and the West border of Russia. It is an ancient city known from 1067. The first written document of the Belarusan statehood goes as far back as 980 AD when Prince Rogvold began his reign on Polotsk lands - the historic and religious center of the Belarusan nation and culture. Belarus became a fast growing state early on in its history, making close trade ties with German (Hansa) cities, with Scandinavia, and neighboring eastern and southern principalities. During its long history it was several times ruined by foreign invaders. When the Red Army soldiers and partisans liberated the city during World War II, 95% of Minsk lay in ruins. Only after many years the Belarusans managed to restore the city. Now Minsk has a population of 1.8 million and Belarus gained its independence in 1991. Belarus has retained closer political and economic ties to Russia than any of the other former Soviet republics, signing a treaty on a two-state union on 8 December 1999 with Russia, envisioning greater political and economic integration. Although Belarus agreed to a framework to carry out the accord, serious implementation has yet to take place. </history>
			<historyClue>This country has retained closer political and economic ties to Russia than any of the other former Soviet republics, signing a treaty on a two-state union on 8 December 1999 with Russia, envisioning greater political and economic integration.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Ukraine</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Bulgaria" capital="Sofia" flag="bulgariaB">
			<flagMeaning>The origins and the meaning of the Bulgarian flag are quite diverse and not clearly defined. The best explanation found so far is the one from Kiril Tanev: "The white means peace and freedom; the green reflects Bulgaria's natural environment - beautiful mountains and fields; and the red is "the blood of all national heroes who died for the liberation and freedom of our country"</flagMeaning>
			<history>Bulgaria is located on the European continent. It belongs to a group of South-eastern European countries called "The Balkans". The Balkans include: Greece, Bulgaria, Albania, Croatia, Slovenia, Serbia, Bosnia and the European part of Turkey. The name originally comes from the Balkan Mountains sited in Bulgaria. Founded in 681, Bulgaria is one of the oldest European states. The First Bulgarian Kingdom existed from 681 till 1018. In this period Bulgaria was converted to Christianity (865), and in the 10th century Bulgarian Prince Simeon received a royal sceptre from Constantinople. Bulgaria was recognized as a tzardom by the Pope and the Holy Roman Empire. In 1018 Emperor Basil II Bulgaroctonus conquered Bulgaria and made it a province of the Byzantine Empire. The Second Bulgarian Kingdom (1185-1396) was initiated after a successful uprising of the Bulgarian aristocracy. Throughout this period, Bulgaria continued to struggle with the Byzantine Empire to assert its place in the Balkans, but by the end of the 14th century the country was overrun by the Ottoman Turks. At the price of its independence, Bulgaria blocked the Sultan's expansion to Europe. Bulgaria was an Ottoman province over the course of the next five centuries. The Third Bulgarian Kingdom stemmed from the San Stephano peace Treaty signed on 3 March 1878. This treaty re-established Bulgaria in its ethnic boundaries determined by a special international committee, but it was revised only several months later by the then Great Powers - Germany, Great Britain, France, Austria-Hungary and Russia. After the restoration of the national state in 1878, Bulgaria became a constitutional monarchy with a democratic governmental system and a rapidly growing economy. In 1946, Bulgaria became a People's Republic. Following 10 November 1989, when under the pressure of both domestic and international developments Todor Zhivkov, Bulgaria's long-time Communist Party leader, was forced to resign, and communist domination ended in 1990.  Bulgaria began the contentious process of moving toward political democracy and a market economy again while combating inflation, unemployment, corruption, and crime. </history>
			<historyClue>Founded in 681, this country is one of the oldest European states. The San Stephano peace Treaty signed on 3 March 1878, re-established its ethnic boundaries determined by a special international committee, but it was revised only several months later by the then Great Powers - Germany, Great Britain, France, Austria-Hungary and Russia.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Greece</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Czech Republic" capital="Prague" flag="czechB">
			<flagMeaning>As with the Bulgarian flag, the theories on the flag colours are multiple. Here is one of them: the red and white in this flag represents the Bohemian people; the blue represents the Slovakians of Moravia.</flagMeaning>
			<history>The Czech Republic is sited on the European continent. It is located on the Eastern border of Germany. Following the First World War, the closely related Czechs and Slovaks of the former Austro-Hungarian Empire merged to form Czechoslovakia. The second half of the 14th century was dominated by the rule of Charles IV and is the most famous era of Czech history. Charles, a fine diplomat, strengthened the political position of the country significantly - not only was he King of Bohemia, but also Emperor of the Holy Roman Empire. Outstanding political and cultural advances were made during his reign. In 1348 he founded the Charles University, the oldest in Central Europe and inaugurated the building of the New Town (Nove Mesto) area in Prague as well as the laying of the Charles Bridge. To these ends, he employed the known artist, Matthew of Arras (Matyas z Arrasu), and the famous architect, Petr Parler. In 1415, at the end of the Hussite Wars, the country underwent a new wave of progress and Prague became once again a center of science and culture in Europe. The unsuccessful Stavovska revolution of 1620 meant an end to political sovereignty and the Thirty Years' War led to major economic decline. After World War II, the political system in Czechoslovakia was greatly affected by the introduction of a Soviet-style Communist regime and in March 1948, the Communist Party became the only autonomous political entity. With the collapse of Soviet Communist regime in 1989, Czechoslovakia regained its freedom. On 1 January 1993, the country gained its independence and underwent a "velvet divorce" into its two national components, the Czech Republic and Slovakia. It is expected to join the European Union (EU) in 2004.</history>
			<historyClue>On 1 January 1993, the country gained its independence and underwent a "velvet divorce" into its two national components, the other being Slovakia.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Poland</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Denmark" capital="Copenhagen" flag="denmarkB">
			<flagMeaning>The Danish flag is called "Dannebrog". In old Danish it stands for "The Danish Cloth". Legend has it that the "Dannebrog" fell from the skies on 15 June 1219, the day in which King Waldemar II defeated the Estonians in battle. The white cross represents Christianity.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Denmark is part of the European continent. The oldest existing evidence of human habitation in Denmark is traces of hunters' settlements from the end of the last Ice Age c. 12500 BC. Organised farming communities did not appear until the Neolithic Age c. 3900 BC and villages are known from the centuries before Christ's birth. Regular towns, such as Ribe, do not appear until the Germanic Iron Age c. 400-750 AD. The unification of the country under a central power began 700 AD. Originally the land of the Vikings c. 800-1100, this period of Denmark's history was characterised by the frequent Viking expeditions which led to the conquest of England for a short period in the 11th century and took the pillaging Vikings as far away as Ireland, Northern France and Russia. The period 1560-1720 was dominated by the intensified rivalry with the neighbouring Sweden, triggering six wars between the two nations. In 1945 Denmark was invited to become a founding member of the United Nations; and in 1949, along with Norway, it joined NATO thus definitively abandoning the policy of neutrality which had been a key element in Denmark's security policy since 1864. Today, Denmark is a modern and prosperous country.</history>
			<historyClue>This country's history is characterised by the frequent Viking expeditions which led to the conquest of England for a short period in the 11th century.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Germany</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Latvia" capital="Riga" flag="latviaB">
			<flagMeaning>The following quotation is from Dr. Karlis Ulmanis, the last President of Latvia before the Soviet invasion in 1940. It describes the meaning of the Latvian flag colours. "White stands for right and truth, the honor of free citizens and trustworthiness. But the red reminds us of the blood that has been shed in the recent past. It has been shed at all times in the remote past and we are ready to offer it again for freedom and independence, for our nation and country."</flagMeaning>
			<history>The name "Latvia" originates from an ancient Baltic  (Indo-European) tribe - the Latgalians (in Latvian: latgali), who formed the ethnic core of the Latvian people. Latvia is now part of the European continent after a brief period of independence between the two wars following which it belonged to the Soviet Union from 1940 up until 1991 when it re-established its independence; although the last Russian troops did not move out until 1994. In the second half of the 1990s Latvia began to set up a modern, guarded eastern border, which is expected to become the eastern border of the European Union in the future. At the end of 1999 in Helsinki the heads of the European Union countries and governments invited Latvia to begin negotiations regarding accession to the European Union. It is predicted in Riga, the capital, that Latvia will become a member of the European Union during the upcoming years.</history>
			<historyClue>Now part of the European continent, it belonged to the Soviet Union from 1940 up until 1991 when it re-established its independence.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Estonia</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Poland" capital="Warsaw" flag="polandB">
			<flagMeaning>The white and red are the national colours of Poland, symbolising a white eagle being on the top of a red crest.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Poland is located on the European continent, between Germany and Ukraine. It is an ancient nation that was conceived around the middle of the 10th century.The name of Poland comes from the name of the Polanie tribe or people tilling land. From the 10th through to the 12th century, Poland was a monarchy, as were many other states of the early Middle Ages, treated by the ruler as their rightful property and heritage - a patriarchy. Poland was first unified as a nation in the 11th century. It was subsequently divided into principalities again, and reunified in the 14th century. The country reached the height of its grandeur in the 16th century, when it was one of the most important powers in Europe, with territories stretching from the Baltic to the Black Sea. In the 17th century Poland came under attack from all sides; it was invaded by the Swedes, fought with the Turks, and there was a Cossack rebellion in the southeastern territories. The country's power was whittled away until at the end of the 18th century Russia, Austria and Prussia together divided Poland up in a series of three partitions. Throughout the 19th century Poland continued to be occupied, despite two uprisings in 1830 and 1863. Independence finally came with the end of WWI. At the end of WWII the communists had seized power accompanied by a harsh Stalinist period of repressions. Poland continued to experience hardship until the 1990s when the seemingly impossible happened. With the opposition continuing to chip away at the monolith of communism, the Communist party was finally disbanded and a democratic government established, enabling the country to transform its economy into one of the most robust in Central Europe inspite of suffering low GDP growth and high unemployment. Poland is scheduled to accede to the European Union on the 1st of May 2004.</history>
			<historyClue>The country reached the height of its grandeur in the 16th century, when it was one of the most important powers in Europe, with territories stretching from the Baltic to the Black Sea.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Czech Republic</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Spain" capital="Madrid" flag="spainB">
			<flagMeaning>The red and yellow colours of the Spanish flag does not have any particular meaning. Following a flag design context in 1785, the current Spanish flag was chosen over 11 other designs. The reason for this choice is likely to be the fact that the flag was clearly distinct from the colours of the other European countries so it could be recognized from a long distance. The coat of arms (in Spanish "blazon") on the flag is a composite symbol. The kingdom of Spain has been made up of several kingdoms: Castille, Leon, Aragon and Navarre. The blazon is made up of all of them. The pink lion on the right upper part of the shield stands for Leon, the Tower on the left upper part of the shield is the coat of arms of Castille, the yellow and the red colours are the colours of Aragon and a chained shield with a crown above is the coat of arms of Navarre.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Spain is part of the European continent. Following the discovery of America (Christopher Columbus was financed by the Crown of Castille), Spain became the most powerful empire during the 16th and 17th century when it reached its height and declined under the Hapsburgs. The Spanish empire reached its greatest magnitude under Charles I, who was also (as Charles V) emperor of the Holy Roman Empire. Under his sucessor Philip II, rising inflation, the expulsion of the Jews and Moors from Spain, combined with the dependency of Spain on New World gold and silver resulted in multiple bankruptcies and economic crashes in Spain. The riches of America were directed to pay the loans of European bankers like the Fugger, that funded the costly wars in defense of Catholicism and the dynastic interests. Under Phillip II, Spain also suffered the inglorious defeat of its Armada - as the Spanish Hapsburgs declined, they ultimately yielded command of the seas to England. On July 17, 1936 Francisco Franco led a right wing coup d'etat against the Second Spanish Republic which was to be the start of the devastating, three-year Spanish Civil War, finally ending on April 1 1939. Spain remained neutral in World Wars I and II. Having failed to follow industrial revolutions, Spain fell behind France, Britain and Germany and is only now beginning to catch up economically, becoming a member of the European Union (former EEC) in 1986.</history>
			<historyClue>Under Phillip II, this country suffered the inglorious defeat of its Armada and ultimately having to yield command of the seas to England.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>France</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Sweden" capital="Stockholm" flag="swedenB">
			<flagMeaning>There are many legends surrounding the colours of the Swedish flag. One of them is the story of a king who, on the eve of a battle, saw in the blue evening sky a yellow cross telling him that the battle would be won and he emblazoned his personal banner and of course the battle was won. Others believe that the blue represents the lakes and the evening sky and that the gold represents the sun.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Sweden is part of the European continent. Swedish history comprises more than 10,000 years and starts after the last glacial period. The long process of creating political unity started about 1100 A.D. During the course of its history, Sweden has received many important influences from abroad. Most prominent was probably the German influence during the Middle Ages, when the Hanseatic League dominated trade in northern Europe. French culture, on the other hand, was adopted at court and among the upper class in the 18th century, while German cultural influence had a revival in the 19th century. The period from about 1750 to 1850 saw a far-reaching modernisation of agriculture that caused a mass exodus of almost one million people in the late 19th and early 20th centuries owing to an increase in a population of non-farmers and no farm land. Throughout WWI and WWII, Sweden managed to stay neutral, and it is this neutrality that has kept Sweden out of conflicts for the past 200 years. Sweden has been a member of the European Union since 1995.</history>
			<historyClue>The period from about 1750 to 1850 saw a far-reaching modernisation of agriculture that caused a mass exodus of almost one million people in the late 19th and early 20th centuries owing to an increase in a population of non-farmers and no farm land.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Finland</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Ukraine" capital="Kiev" flag="ukrainB">
			<flagMeaning>The blue symbolises the colour of the skies, mountains and streams; the yellow represents the golden fields. According to Elias Granqvist, the blue and yellow of Ukraine came from the Swedish flag. When King Carl XII of Sweden (1697-1718) went to war against Peter the Great of Russia, he made allies with the Ukrainians, who wanted sovereignty from Russia. The Ukrainians would, therefore, have taken up the colours of Sweden as their colours. This could be a feasible explanation however, this theory has yet to be proven.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Ukraine is part of the European continent. Former land of the Cossacks (skilled horse riders), Ukrainian territories had been absorbed by the Russian Empire. Ukrainian people suffered a long period of domination by the Russian Empire. Despite such repression and severe Tsarist autocratic rule, Ukraine in the 17th and 18th centuries nonetheless managed to preserve and enjoy some of the richness of its political, economic, cultural, and religious development. The Kyiv Mohyla Academy, founded by Metropolitan Petro Mohyla in the 17th century, became the first university in Eastern Europe. In that period, the Ukrainian people were among the most educated in the world and almost all were literate. Books were printed, philosophy was studied; music, literature and painting flourished. The first Constitution appeared in Ukraine during the Cossack period (1711). 
It is the largest state in Europe and it appeared on the map of the world in 1991 when on the collapse of the Soviet Union it gained its independence. It was quickly recognized by the international community and more then 100 countries have established diplomatic relations with Ukraine. However, many of the former Soviet elite remain entrenched, stalling efforts at economic reform, privatisation, and civil liberties.</history>
			<historyClue>It is the largest state in Europe and it appeared on the map of the world in 1991 when on the collapse of the Soviet Union it gained its independence.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Romania</geoClue>
		</country>
	</continent>

	<continent name="Africa">
		<country name="Angola" capital="Luanda" flag="angolaB">
			<flagMeaning>In the middle a golden star, part of a cog wheel and a machete - believed to be inspired by Russia's hammer and sickle - representing industrial and agricultural workers; the yellow is to represent mineral wealth, and red and black are said to stand for 'Freedom or Death'.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Angola is located on the West coast of Africa. Modern Angola derives its name from the king of Ndongo, NGOLA.As far back as as 1,000 years ago, Angola was inhabited by peoples speaking Bantu languages, engaged in agriculture with iron tools and trade over long distances. In 1482, the Portuguese first landed in what is now northern Angola and soon established control over the port cities of Luanda and Benguela, gradually taking control of the coastal strip throughout the 16th century by a series of treaties and wars. Portugal's primary interest in Angola quickly turned to slavery. The slaving system began early in the 16th century with the purchase from African chiefs of people to work on sugar plantations in Sao Tome, Principe, and Brazil. Many scholars agree that by the 19th century, Angola was the largest source of slaves not only for Brazil, but for the Americas, including the United States. By the end of the 19th century, a massive forced labor system had replaced formal slavery and would continue until outlawed in 1961. Portugal took full administrative control of the interior at the beginning of the 20th century characterised by rigid dictatorship and exploitation of African labor. It was this forced labor that provided the basis for development of a plantation economy and, by the mid-20th century, a major mining sector. Forced labor, combined with British financing, was used to construct three railroads from the coast to the interior, the most important of which was the transcontinental Benguela railroad that linked the port of Lobito with the copper zones of the Belgian Congo and what is now Zambia. In their war for independence, which began in 1961, Angolans were divided; the tribal-based (FNLA), the Maoist (UNITA), and the Maoist and broadly-based (MPLA) were all strong groups fighting the Portuguese. A 1974 coup d'etat in Portugal established a military government that promptly ceased the war and agreed to hand over power to a coalition of the three movements. Portugal granted Angola independence on November 11, 1975. However, in 1995 localized fighting resumed and serious fighting resumed in late 1998. The extended civil wars rendered hundreds of thousands of people homeless. Up to 1.5 million lives may have been lost in fighting over the past quarter century. In August 2002, the civil war was finally ended. Angola is currently at peace under the leadership of the MPLA and Dos Santos, although still facing huge social and economic problems as a result of almost continual war since 1975, and Portuguese colonialism for decades before that.</history>
			<historyClue>Portugal's primary interest in this country quickly turned to slavery. The slaving system began early in the 16th century and by the 19th century this country was the largest source of slaves not only for Brazil, but for the Americas, including the United States.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Namibia</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Chad" capital="N'Djamena" flag="chadB">
			<flagMeaning>The blue-yellow-red colours of Chad are a combination of the blue-white-red of France, the former colonial power, and the green-yellow-red of Pan-Africa.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Chad is part of the African continent. Chad's history dates back as far as 2,500 years ago. In the early 19th century, the black Africans in southern Chad became the focus of slave raids by the Arabs, selling for the price of a horse. In the early 20th century, the French arrived in Chad, abolishing the slave trade and making Chad a French colony until 1960 when independence was finally granted. The southerners took charge, displeasing the northerners, who viewed the black Africans as either subjects or slaves; certainly not leaders. Poor and unstable in its independence, things only got worse with the onset of cyclical droughts from the late 1960s. Unrest turned into civil war. Like its neighbours, Chad fell into a pattern of military crackdowns and attempted coups. In 1992 and 1993 there were five attempted coups and numerous crackdowns. In one of these, 15,000 civilians fled to the Central African Republic following massacres allegedly by government troops. Since then it has had to face constant ethnic warfare (war of races), and also to survive invasions from Libya. A peace agreement (signed in 2002) and although Chad has enjoyed a period of relative peace and close relations with Libya over the past few years, conflict is never far away. Guerrilla raids are still common in the Tibesti region of northern Chad (despite accords signed in 2002 and 2003 with the MDJT and National Resistance Army rebel groups) and armed clashes with Nigerian forces occur occasionally around Lake Chad over ongoing demarcation issues. </history>
			<historyClue>Like its neighbours, this country fell into a pattern of military crackdowns and attempted coups. In one of these, 15,000 civilians fled to the Central African Republic following massacres allegedly by government troops.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Lybia</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Ivory Coast" capital="Yamoussoukro" flag="ivoryB">
			<flagMeaning>Orange represents the colour of the people's land, rich and generous; it also symbolises their fight - the blood of young people fighting for liberation. White is for peace, but peace with justice. Green is for hope and the certainty of a better future. The vertical positions are influenced by the French tricolour (blue white red).</flagMeaning>
			<history>Ivory Coast (most of the time called 'Cote d'Ivoire') is part of the African continent. One of the smallest African countries, the Cote d'Ivoire is a country of extraordinary cultural richness. While the southern coastal area has for the last several decades served as an archetype of prosperity and modernisation, the northern and western regions of the Cote d'Ivoire are home to two fascinating and vital traditional cultures - the Senufo and the Dan.
Maintaining close ties with France (French is still the official language) after its independence from France in 1960, and the development and exportation of cocoa along with foreign investment, made Ivory Coast one of the most prosperous of the tropical African states . However, in the 1980s the country's economy began to suffer, followed rapidly by political unrest when a military coup - the first ever in Cote d'Ivoire's history - overthrew the government led by President Henri Konan BEDIE on 25 December 1999. Towards the end of 2002, rebel forces claimed the northern half of the country and in January 2003 were granted ministerial positions in a unity government. Today, several thousand French and West African troops remain in Cote d'Ivoire to maintain peace and help implement the peace accords. </history>
			<historyClue>Towards the end of 2002, rebel forces claimed the northern half of the country and in January 2003 were granted ministerial positions in a unity government. Today, several thousand French and West African troops remain in this country to maintain peace and help implement the peace accords.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Ghana</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Egypt" capital="Cairo" flag="egyptB">
			<flagMeaning>The colour red predates the 1952 Revolution - a period characterised by the struggle against the British occupation of the country. The white symbolises the advent of the 1952 Revolution which ended the monarchy without bloodshed (a group of army officers to power after unseating King Farouk, then King of Egypt). The colour black symbolises the end of the oppression of the people of Egypt at the hands of the Monarchy and British colonialism. The golden eagle in the middle of the flag is the eagle of Saladdin, a Sultan who ruled Egypt and Syria in 12th Century.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Egypt is part of the African continent. The history of Egypt is very rich and goes back more than 5000 years ago. The Nile's (the world's longest river) fertile banks - the source of economic, social, political and religious life - gave rise to one of the world's great civilisations, with the first unified kingdom evolving c.3200 B.C. and a series of dynasties of pharaohs ruling Egypt for the next three millennia. The last native dynasty fell to the Persians in 341 B.C., who in turn were replaced by the Greeks, Romans, and Byzantines. Napoleon invaded in 1798, only to be ousted by the British in 1801, in turn expelled by Mohammed Ali, a lieutenant in the Albanian contingent of the Ottoman army. Said Pasha, Ali's grandson, opened the Suez Canal in 1869 and Egypt became an important world transportation hub but also fell heavily into debt. The British seized control of Egypt's government in 1882 and in 1922, after having been partially under Britain's rule for 40 years, Egypt finally acquired full sovereignty following WWII.</history>
			<historyClue>The Nile's fertile banks - the source of economic, social, political and religious life - gave rise to one of the world's great civilisations, with the first unified kingdom evolving c.3200 B.C.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Sudan</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Gabon" capital="Libreville" flag="gabonB">
			<flagMeaning>The colours, green, yellow and blue very simply stand for the forest, the Equator line (which crosses the country) and the sea, respectively.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Gabon is part of the African continent. Pre 15th century, Gabon's history is unclear but what is clear is that in a very short time - less than 400 years - tribal social structures did a 180 degree turnaround, from its first contact with Europeans - the Portuguese in 1472 -  to Gabon's then capital, Libreville, becoming a settlement for freed slaves in 1849, and a mecca for every god-faring missionary in the western world soon after. In 1904, the capital was transferred from Libreville to Brazzaville, and six years later Gabon became a French colony in French Equatorial Africa. During the early years of the 20th century, when colonisation was still seen as an economic rather than a social or ethical issue, French private companies exploited Gabon by forcing Africans to work for them. Having only recently thrown off the shackles of slavery, the Gabonese were understandably bent out of shape by this new form of indentured slavery and, like other Africans in French Equatorial Africa, vented their anger in periodic revolts. Each successive revolt was quelled, and by the time a new broom swept these old regimes out of the country the companies had destroyed the forests, used up most of the other natural resources and sent the country into an economic slump that lasted until after WWI. In 1960 Gabon acquired independence. Thirty years later, in 1990, civil unrest led to the legalisation of political parties for the purpose of free elections and reforms of governmental institutions. Gabon is now a prosperous country, thanks to its small population, abundant natural resources and significant foreign support.</history>
			<historyClue>In 1910 this country became a French colony in French Equatorial Africa and during the eary years of the 20th centruy, French private companies managed to exploit and destroy the forests, use up most of the other natural resources and send the country into an economic slump that lasted until after WWI.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Equatorial Guinea</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Kenya" capital="Nairobi" flag="kenyaB">
			<flagMeaning>The flag was adopted on 12 December 1963. It is based on the black above red above green flag of KANU (Kenya African National Union) that epitomised the fight for freedom. The colours symbolise black majority, blood and natural wealth. On Kenya's independence the white fimbriation was added, symbolising peace. The defence of freedom is symbolised by a traditional Masai shield and two spears.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Kenya is located on the South-Eastern coast of the African continent. Kenya had human footsteps stamped on its soil way back in 2000 BC by nomadic Cushitic tribes from Ethiopia. A second group followed around 1000 BC and occupied much of central Kenya. The rest of the ancestors of the country's medley of tribes arrived from all over the continent between 500 BC and AD 500. With the arrival of the Portuguese at the end of the 15th century, the East African coastal region was for a time dominated by the Europeans. However, in 1729 the Portuguese were expelled, to be replaced by two Arab dynasties. Arab rule lasted until the end of the 18th century, when Kenya passed into the British sphere of influence. The country became independent in 1963. Although it has experienced its share of internal and external strife, Kenya has in recent years been moving toward a more stable, multi-party political system.</history>
			<historyClue>This country had human footsteps stamped on its soil way back in 2000 BC by nomadic Cushitic tribes from Ethiopia. The rest of the ancestors of the country's medley of tribes arrived from all over the continent between 500 BC and AD 500.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Tanzania</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Libya" capital="Tripoli" flag="libyaB">
			<flagMeaning>Green is the national colour of Libya as well as a symbol of devotion to Islam.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Libya is located on the South-Eastern coast of the African continent. The Romans invaded the region around Tripoli in 106 BC, and by 64 BC, Julius Caesar's legions had completed the occupation. As a Roman province, Libya was prosperous, reaching a golden age in the 200 AD. 500 AD saw the decline of the Roman Empire and along with it the fall of the Roman cities. In 600 AD the Byzantines took over and tried to restore the old cities but to no avail; the cities collapsed into disuse. The Arab invasion of the 7th century brought Islam to the country, where it remains firmly entrenched to this day. Following the Napoleonic wars, European powers began to colonise northern Africa, and Libya was taken from the Turks by Italy in that country's last-minute bid for colonies in Africa. The Italian colonial period proved devastating for native Libyans, as the large-scale 'Italianisation' of the country saw half of the indigenous population either exiled or exterminated between 1911 and the end of WWII. In the postwar years, Italy was forced to give up Libya, and the country became independent under King Idris. On 1 September 1969, a small group of army officers led by 27-year-old Captain Mu'ammar Gaddafi deposed the old king in a coup. Throughout the 1970s and 1980s, Libya adopted a high international profile based on Pan-Arabism; with Gaddafi alienating Libya from the western world because of his support of real and so-called liberation movements, and particularly his alleged support of international terrorist organisations. In 1999 the UN lifted the sanctions it had imposed on Libya seven years earlier and Gaddafi has been working hard to overturn Libya's 'terrorist state' image.</history>
			<historyClue>In 1999 the UN lifted the sanctions it had imposed on this country seven years earlier, and Gaddafi has been working hard to overturn it's 'terrorist state' image.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Egypt</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Niger" capital="Niamey" flag="nigerB">
			<flagMeaning>The flag of Niger is orange above white above green, with an orange disc on the central white stripe, symbolizing the sun. The orange stands for the Sahara desert, which borders Niger to the north. Green stands for the grassy plains of the south and west, and for the River Niger that sustains them. It also stands for fraternity and hope. White generally symbolises purity and hope. In the Nigerian flag it additionally stands for the savannah region of the country.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Niger used to be a French colony. The first recognisable empire in the region was the Kanem-Bornu Empire that flourished between the 10th and 13th century, and again briefly in the 16th. Niger remained the exclusive province of the sultans until 1898, when the French stormed the country and added yet another name to their list of colonised countries. In 1960, Niger finally gained full independence. The 1973 and 74 droughts had a devastating impact on Niger from which it is still recovering. The 80s saw hard times for Niger with empty promises of reform and a debilitating rebel Tuareg movement. In 1990 rebel warfare, banditry, violent clashes, and general lawlessness continued unabated for over a year over empty promises of financial aid and assistance to preserve the Tuareg culture. In 1991 an interim government was elected to run the country until the multiparty elections of 1992, Nigers first free and open election since its independence. After an unfortunate, accidental gunning down of the President by his own bodyguard in April 1999, a return to democratic rule with peaceful elections in October and November 1999 took place. Niger remains one of the hottest countries in the world. The northern part of its land is crossed by the Sahara desert.</history>
			<historyClue>In 1990 rebel warfare, banditry, violent clashes, and general lawlessness continued unabated for over a year over empty promises of financial aid and assistance to preserve the Tuareg culture.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Nigeria</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Nigeria" capital="Abuja" flag="nigeriaB">
			<flagMeaning>The green panels represent agriculture; the white: peace and unity.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Nigeria is located on the middle East coast of the African continent. The earliest Nigerians were the Nok people, skilled artisans from around the Jos area. By the beginning of the second millennium the Nok had virtually disappeared and the state of Kanem, to the north east of Lake Chad, was flourishing. By contrast the southern states were dominated in the 14th and 15th centuries by a number of Yoruba empires with traditional Obas (kings) who cultivated European contact through the Portugese spice trade. This division between the Islamic government in the north and the Yoruba tribes in the south has never healed even today, and over the years intertribal fighting and civil wars have rubbed salt into the wounds. After the bottom fell out of the spice trade, the Portugese, and then the British, began trading in the human misery of slaves, but by 1807 slavery had been banned and British companies began to take control of the Jos mines, destroying the livelihood of thousands of independent tin producers. Worse was to come, the heavy reliance on mining exports was achieved at the expense of Nigeria's export food crops and the country had its first-ever food shortage. In 1960 Nigeria declared independence but the historical conflicts between north and south, and other inter-regional fighting, made the idea of a unified republic unworkable. By 1966 the dream of a flourishing democracy was floundering amidst a series of massacres, inter-regional hostilities and, finally, a military coup that installed the first of a series of military governments which lasted until 1999 when Nigeria was returned to civilian rule with the election of a non-military president, Olusegun Obasanjo. Despite some irregularities the April 2003 elections marked the first civilian transfer of power in Nigeria's history.</history>
			<historyClue>After the bottom fell out of the spice trade, the Portugese, and then the British, began trading in the human misery of slaves, but by 1807 slavery had been banned and British companies began to take control of the Jos mines, destroying the livelihood of thousands of independent tin producers.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Cameroon</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Rwanda" capital="Kigali" flag="rwandaB">
			<flagMeaning>Rwanda's flag is very recent (2001). The meaning of its colours are: green the symbol of hope of prosperity thanks to rational exploitation of the force of Rwandan people and the resources of the country; yellow the symbol of economic development - the Rwandan people must settle to work so as to reach durable economic development; blue is the symbol of happiness and peace - the Rwandan people must fight for peace which will bring the economic development that will give them happiness; the sun and its rays of golden colour symbolise the light that enlightens gradually all the people. This translates as unity, transparency and fight against ignorance.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Rwanda used to be a Belgian colony. Its history has been dominated by the violent interaction between its two largest ethnic groups, the Tutsis and the Hutus. In its earliest history however, the region now known as Rwanda was home to the pygmy Twa, a group now accounting for only about 1% of Rwanda's population and playing only a marginal role in Rwandan life. The Twa were replaced by the migration of today's ethnic Hutus and the Tutsis coming from east Africa. Contrary to creating a unified community with the Hutus being agriculturalists and the Tutsis farmers, the Hutus became enfeuded to the Tutsis with the Tutsis becoming masters, while the Hutus became the servants. The next important period in Tutsi/Hutu relations was the colonial period. In 1885, the conference of Berlin gave Rwanda and Burundi to the German Empire as colonial spheres of interest. Nine years later, the first Europeans arrived in Rwanda. Rwanda entered into another period in its history as Germany was ousted from its African colonies at the end of World War I. Belgium became the new possessor of Rwanda. Following World War II, reforms instituted by the Belgians in the 1950s encouraged the growth of democratic political institutions but were resisted by the Tutsi traditionalists who saw them as a threat to Tutsi rule. In November 1959, the Hutu overthrew King Kigeri V, the last Tutsi monarch. During the 1959 revolt and its aftermath, more than 160,000 Tutsis fled to neighboring countries. A June 1962 UN General Assembly resolution terminated the Belgian trusteeship and granted full independence to Rwanda effective July 1, 1962. By April 1991 100,000 were dead, by May, 200,000, and by May's end, half a million. The war dragged on for almost 2 years until a ceasefire accord was signed July 12, 1992, in Arusha, Tanzania, fixing a timetable for an end to the fighting and political talks, leading to a peace accord, powersharing, and authorisation of a neutral military observer group under the auspices of the Organization for African Unity. A ceasefire took effect July 31, 1992, and political talks began August 10, 1992. Despite substantial international assistance and political reforms - including Rwanda's first ever local elections held in March 1999 - the country continues to struggle to boost investment and agricultural output and to foster reconciliation.</history>
			<historyClue>Its history has been dominated by the violent interaction between its two largest ethnic groups, the Tutsis and the Hutus.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Burundi</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Tunisia" capital="Tunis" flag="tunisiaB">
			<flagMeaning>The white disc in the centre represents the sun. It contains a red Osmanli (Turkish) crescent and a five-pointed star - the two ancient symbols of Islam. The shape of the waxing moon (from the point of view of an Arab observer of the flag) brings luck. Red became the symbol of resistance against Turkish supremacy.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Tunisia is the smallest country in North Africa, but its strategic position has ensured it an eventful history. The earliest hard evidence of human inhabitation was unearthed near the southern oasis town of Kebili and dates back about 200,000 years. Up until 700 BC the Phoenicians, Romans, Vandals (Germanic people belonging to the family of East Germans), Byzantines all had their turn of power. Then the next 50 years saw Tunisia under the Arabs, Berbers, Spain and finally the Ottoman Empire, being taken by the Turks in the middle of the 16th century. The Ottoman power lasted through to the 19th century when France became the new power and Tunis was forced to conform to European ways until 1956 when Habib BOURGUIBA led the independence movement and France finally gave Tunisia its independence. BOURGUIBA then became the first Tunisian President establishing a strict one-party state; ruling the country for 31 years, repressing Islamic fundamentalism and establishing rights for women unmatched by any other Arab nation.</history>
			<historyClue>BOURGUIBA became this country's first President establishing a strict one-party state; repressing Islamic fundamentalism and establishing rights for women unmatched by any other Arab nation.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Algeria</geoClue>
		</country>
	</continent>

	<continent name="North America">
		<country name="The Bahamas" capital="Nassau" flag="bahamasB">
			<flagMeaning>The flag is 30 years old (very young). According to Smith (1975): 'The golden sands of the 700 Bahamian islands are reflected in the centre of the flag, while the aquamarine stripes bring to mind the various shades of ocean waters around those islands.  The black triangle indicates the unity of the Bahamian people in their determination to develop the resources of both land and sea.' This interpretation had then been contested but nobody could give a better explanation.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Geography played a crucial role in Bahamian history. The original inhabitants of The Bahamas were the Lucayans, a tribe of the Arawak Indian group, who arrived near the turn of the 9th century living peacefully until in 1492, Christopher Columbus made his first landfall in the New World on the island of San Salvador in the eastern Bahamas. After observing the shallow sea around the islands, he said "baja mar" (shallow water or sea), and effectively named the area The Bahamas, or The Islands of the Shallow Sea. Three years later the Bahamas became a Spanish colony with the Lucayans enslaved by the Spaniards for shipment to Hispaniola. 25 years later with the entire Lucayan population of 50,000 gone, the Spaniards moved out leaving the Bahamas unsettled and unclaimed until over a century later when King Charles I of England granted them to his attorney general and the Bahamas became a  British colony. The 1900s saw poverty and illicit trading for the Bahamas. After WWII the islands' new high profile governor and governess, the Duke and Duchess of Windsor, formerly King Edward VIII of England, gave the islands a new luster by rekindling tourism for the wealthy, and making the country a corporate tax haven.  On 10 July 1973, the islands of the Bahamas officially became a new nation, the Commonwealth of The Bahamas, ending 325 years of British rule.</history>
			<historyClue>In 1492, Christopher Columbus made his first landfall in the New World on the island of San Salvador. After observing the shallow sea around the islands, he said "baja mar" (shallow water or sea).</historyClue>
			<geoClue>this chain of islands sits in the North Atlantic Ocean</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Canada" capital="Ottawa" flag="canadaB">
			<flagMeaning>The maple leaf has been Canada's emblem since 1860. The red in the flag does not really have any meaning but as Canada used to be a British colony, it could be interpreted as the red and white echo the British "Union Jack" flag.When the Prince of Wales visits Canada, as a sign of respect all the Canadians of English origin had to wear a rose, those of Scottish origin had to wear a thistle (another type of flower), but the Canadians could not wear their current emblem - a beaver, so they chose to wear a maple leaf (symbol at that time of a French-Canadian society). When Canada gained its independence from England, in 1867, the maple leaf became their flag.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Canada is located on the upper part of the North American continent. It is is the second biggest country in the world (after Russia) and also known as 'The Great White North' for its wide-open spaces and icy winters. Canada, which has been inhabited by natives including the First Nations and the Inuit for about 10,000 years, was first visited by Europeans around 1000, when the Vikings briefly settled at L'Anse aux Meadows in Newfoundland. More permanent European visits came in the 16th and 17th century, as the English and French settled here. In 1763, at the end of the Seven Years' War, France decided to keep its Caribbean Islands and leave its North American colony, New France, to Britain. After the American Revolution, many British Loyalists settled in Canada. United States and the United Kingdom fought the War of 1812. On July 1, 1867 with the passing of the British North America Act, the British government granted local self-government to a confederation of three of its North American colonies as the Dominion of Canada. In later years, other British colonies and territories joined the confederation. Full control over its affairs came in 1931 with the Statute of Westminster, and in 1982 with the patriation of Canada's constitution. On July 7, 1969 the French language was given equal status with the English language throughout the Canadian federal government. This started a process that led to Canada redefining itself as a bilingual and multicultural nation. In the late second half of the 20th century, some citizens of the French-speaking province of Quebec have sought independence in two referendums held in 1980 and 1995. In both cases, the referendums were defeated with 60% and 50.6% opposed to independence, respectively.</history>
			<historyClue>In the late second half of the 20th century, some citizens of the French-speaking province of Quebec have sought independence in two referendums held in 1980 and 1995. In both cases, the referendums were defeated with 60% and 50.6% opposed to independence, respectively.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>USA</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Cuba" capital="Havana" flag="cubaB">
			<flagMeaning>The Cuban flag was designed in 1848 by Narciso Lopez during the first serious attempt to break the country free from Spain. According to Lopez, the three blue stripes represented Cuba's three provinces - Western, Eastern and Central - at that time. The white symbolised the purity and justice of the patriotic liberators' motives. The lone white star within the triangle stood for the unity of the people and the colour red signified the blood spilled by the revolutionary heroes.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Cuba is located on the South-East part of the continent, in the Caribbean sea. Before 1492, Cuba was populated by two very distinct aborigine groups: Ta no and Siboney or Ciboney; both were Stone Age cultures. During the Spanish conquest (led by Diego Velquez de Cullar), the entire native indian population was wiped out due to the cruelty of spanish conquistadores, and the diseases they brought with them and which were previously unknown to the indian, such as measles. On October 28, 1492, the first European, Christopher Columbus stepped on to the island. For the next four decades Cuba remained under Spanish rule until in December of 1898, Spain relinquished control of Cuba to the United States with the Treaty of Paris as a result of the Spanish-American war. The US then occupied Cuba for the following five years and on May 20, 1902, the United States 'granted' Cuba its independence, but retained the right to intervene to preserve Cuban independence and stability, making the independence in name only, enabling the US to 'plunder' the island's resources and riches at will. Following the departure of the American forces on 28 January  1909, Cuba fell victim to violent dictatorships, uprisings and polictical corruption, not least the Batista Regime when Fulgencio Batista became President in 1940. In 1958 Fidel Castro started a revolution that ended a year later with the victory of Castro forces. For the next 30 years, Castro pursued closer relations with the Soviet Union until the demise of the USSR in 1991. When USSR support was lost, Cuba's economy was essentially paralysed, and living conditions in Cuba worsened. This led Castro to open the country to tourism from Europe and Asia, and to enter into several joint ventures with foreign companies for hotel, agricultural and industrial projects. In 2001, a group backed by the powerful Catholic church collected thousands of signatures for the Varela Project, a petition requesting a referendum on the island's political system. The process was openly supported by former U.S. president Jimmy Carter during his historic 2002 visit to Cuba. In response, Castro backers formally proclaimed that Castro's brand of socialism would be perpetual.</history>
			<historyClue>In 2001, a group backed by the powerful Catholic church collected thousands of signatures for the Varela Project, a petition requesting a referendum on the island's political system. The process was openly supported by former U.S. president Jimmy Carter during his historic 2002 visit to this country.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>this island sits between the North Atlantic Ocean and the Caribbean Sea</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Greenland" capital="Nuuk (Godthab)" flag="greenlandB">
			<flagMeaning>Greenland's flag does not have any historic background since it is only decades rather than centuries old. Greenland used to be part of Denmark hence the influence of the red and white colours (Denmark's flag colours). According to the flag designer (Thue Christiansen), the large white half symbolises the ice cap and the white half of the circle symbolises the ice bergs and the packed ice; the red half of the circle represents the fjords while the large red part of the flag represents the ocean.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Greenland is located on the North East part of the North American continent. The first people to find their way to the world's largest island arrived about 5,000 years ago from what's now northern Canada. Over time, several different cultural groups migrated to the island. The Thule (pronounced TOO-lay), ancestors of the Inuit who form the indigenous people of Greenland, arrived in the early 900s AD. They were soon joined by Scandinavians when Eric the Red established a Viking colony on the island in the 980s. The European settlements flourished for a time, but by the 1400s, the Scandinavian presence had withered. It wasn't until the 1700s that Danes and Norwegians again established outposts. In 1814 Denmark got political control of Greenland, and it continues to play a large role in island affairs. When Germany extended its war operations to Greenland, Henrik Kauffmann, the Danish Minister to the United States - who had already refused to recognise the German occupation of Denmark - signed a treaty with the USA on April 9, 1941, placing Greenland under US protection and granting US forces permission to establish stations there. A home-rule government was instituted in 1979, which provides for a great deal of local autonomy in day-to-day affairs. Denmark remains responsible for issues such as defense and foreign affairs.  Nearly 25% of the population live in the capital, NUUK.</history>
			<historyClue>In 1814 Denmark got political control of this country, and when Germany extended its war operations to this country, the Danish Minister to the United States signed a treaty with the USA on April 9, 1941, placing it under US protection and granting US forces permission to establish stations there.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>this island sits between the Arctic and North Atlantic Ocean</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Honduras" capital="Tegucigalpa" flag="hondurasB">
			<flagMeaning>The flag was adopted in 1949. It is the same as the one that Honduras had when it became a member of the Central American federation in 1821. The blue and white stripe was the colour of the federation and the 5 white stars were the 5 federation's countries: El Salvador, Costa Rica, Nicaragua, Guatemala and Honduras. Today those five stars on the flag reflect the hope that the 5 states may once again form an association.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Honduras is located on the South-East of the North American continent. In Pre-Columbian times, what is now Honduras was part of the MesoAmerican cultural area. The western part of Honduras was part of the famous Maya civilization; the great Maya culture that flourished in the ancient Maya city state of Copan, near the Guatemalan border, for hundreds of years until the early 9th century. Christopher Columbus landed at mainland Honduras (Trujillo) in 1502. He named it "Honduras" (meaning "depths") for the deep water off the coast. Folllowing the arrival of spaniard Hernan Cortes in 1524 the Spanish began founding settlements along the coast and Honduras came under the control of the Captaincy General of Guatemala. Honduras, along with the other Central American provinces, gained independence from Spain in 1821; when it was briefly annexed to the Mexican Empire. Since independence, Honduras has been plagued with nearly 300 internal rebellions, civil wars, and changes of government - more than half occurring during the 20th century. In 1823, Honduras joined the newly formed United Provinces of Central America. Before long, social and economic differences between Honduras and its regional neighbors intensified harsh partisan strife among Central American leaders and brought on the federation's collapse in 1838 - 1839 following which Honduras declared independence from Mexico. The 20th century saw Honduras play home to three major US fruit companies, and a US military base during the turmoil in Nicaragua, El Salvador and Guatemala. In 1990 Honduras was left in political peace but in 1998 Hurricane Mitch devastated Honduras killing about 5600 people and displacing 1.5 million people. Damages nearly totaled $3billion.</history>
			<historyClue>The 20th century saw this country play home to three major US fruit companies, and a US military base during the turmoil in Nicaragua, El Salvador and Guatemala. In 1990 political peace finally arrived but in 1998 Hurricane Mitch devastated it killing about 5600 people and displacing 1.5 million people.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>El Salvador</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Jamaica" capital="Kingston" flag="jamaicaB">
			<flagMeaning>"Burdens and hardships there may be, but we have hope and the sun still shines" - Jamaica's flag in a nutshell: yellow for sunshine and natural resources; black for the burdens borne by the people; green for agriculture and hope for the future. </flagMeaning>
			<history>Jamaica is located in the Caribbean Sea on the South-East side of the North America continent. Before being discovered by Christopher Columbus, Jamaica was populated by 2 kinds of people: The Arawaks and the Caribs. The Arawaks were a peaceful people while the Caribs were cannibalistic and fierce fighters. Christopher Columbus called this island Jamaica because he heard the natives calling it Xaymaca. Unfortunately for the natives, Columbus and the conquistadors brought with them continental disease (such as smallpox) against which the natives had no defences. The conquistadors enslaved those who survived. After being conquered by the Spanish, Jamaica was colonised by the British. Following unrest and riots in anger at British policy and the People's National Party (PNP) was founded in 1938. Jamaica gained a degree of local political control in the late 1930s. The first democratic election  was held in 1944. Jamaica joined nine other U.K. territories in the Federation of the West Indies in 158 but withdrew after Jamaican voters rejected membership in 1961. Jamaica gained independence on August 6, 1962, remaining a member of the Commonwealth.</history>
			<historyClue>After being conquered by the Spanish, this country was colonised by the British. It joined nine other U.K. territories in the Federation of the West Indies in 1958 but withdrew after voters rejected membership in 1961.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>this island sits in the Caribbean Sea</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Mexico" capital="Mexico" flag="mexicoB">
			<flagMeaning>The Mexican flag is called "La Bandera Nacional". The three colours stand for hope (green), unity, purity and honesty (white), and the red stands for parenthood and the blood of national heroes. The coat of arms in the middle of the white stripe depicts an eagle on a cactus, eating a snake. It recalls an old Aztec legend: "The Aztec people were guided by the god Huitzilopochtli, to seek a place where an eagle landed on a prickly-pear cactus, ating a snake". After hundreds of years of wandering they found the sign on a small swampy island in Lake Texcoco. Their new home they named Mexico-Tenochtitlan ("In the Moon's navel-Place of the Prickly Pear Cactus"). In A.D. 1325 they built a city on the site of the island in the lake; this is now the centre (downtown) of Mexico City.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Mexico is located on the South of the North America continent. Almost 3000 years of civilisation - Olmecs (1200-600 BC), Zapotecs (300 BC), Mayans (250 AD), Toltecs (600 AD) and the Aztecs (early 14th-16th century) - was shattered in just two short years, following the landing by Hernan Cortes near modern-day Veracruz on April 21, 1519. The indigenous population fell from an estimated 25 million at the time of conquest to one million by 1605. New Spain, as Mexico was then known, came under Spanish rule for three centuries until the catalyst for rebellion came in 1808 when Napoleon Bonaparte occupied most of Spain - direct Spanish control over New Spain suddenly ceased and in 1821 Spain agreed to Mexican independence. 22 years of chronic instability followed independence: the presidency changed hands 36 times. 1878-1911 saw dictator Porfirio Diaz avoiding war and piloting Mexico into the industrial age. Political opposition, free elections and a free press were banned, and control was maintained by a ruthless army, leading to strikes that prefigured the Mexican Revolution. The 10 years of violent civil war (1910-1920) cost an estimated 1.5 to two million lives. Following on from this, Mexico experienced economic hardships, not least the massive earthquake of September 1985 causing more than US$4 billion in damage. At least 10,000 people died, hundreds of buildings in Mexico City were destroyed and thousands of people were made homeless. 1994 saw the apex of Mexican economy when under President Carlos Salinas de Grotari Mexico's crippling national debt was renegotiated bringing rising inflation under control. A sweeping privatisation programme and a burgeoning international finance market led to Mexico being heralded in the international press as an exemplar of free-market economics. Unfortunately this did not last when Mexico's currency, the peso, suddenly collapsed, bringing on a rapid and deep economic recession. However, by 2000, the then president, Zedillo, had managed to pull Mexico out of recession and its purchasing power was again reaching its 1994 level. </history>
			<historyClue>Almost 3000 years of civilisation - Olmecs (1200-600 BC), Zapotecs (300 BC), Mayans (250 AD), Toltecs (600 AD) and the Aztecs (early 14th-16th century) - was shattered in just two short years, following the landing by Hernan Cortes near modern-day Veracruz on April 21, 1519.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Guatemala</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Panama" capital="Panama" flag="panamaB">
			<flagMeaning>The blue and red is for the Conservative and Liberal Parties; the white is for peace; the blue star is the purity and honesty of the life of the country; the red star is for authority and law in the country.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Panama is located on the South of the North American continent. The earliest known inhabitants of Panama were the Cuevas and the Cocle cultures, but they were decimated by disease and the sword when the Spanish arrived in the 16th century. Panama went into decline, and became a province of Colombia when the South American nation received its independence in 1821. In 1846, Colombia signed a treaty permitting the USA to construct a railway across the isthmus and to defend it with military force. The idea of a canal across the peninsula had always been a dream for Panamas' rulers and been raised back in the 16th century, but a French attempt to build one in 1880 resulted in the death of 22,000 workers from malaria and yellow fever and bankruptcy for everyone involved.  In 1903 Panama gained its independence from Columbia although Columbia refused to acknowledge it until 1921. A canal treaty granted the USA the rights over land on both sides of the canal and after years of politcal friction between Columbia and USA with Columbia finally being bought off, the USA began to build the canal again in 1904, and 10 years later, the first ship negotiated one of the world's greatest engineering achievements. However, full Panamanian ownership of the canal did not come until December 1999 when the USA finally handed it over.</history>
			<historyClue>With Columbia finally being bought off, the USA began to build the canal again in 1904, and 10 years later, the first ship negotiated one of the world's greatest engineering achievements.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Costa Rica</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Trinidad and Tobago" capital="Port-of-Spain" flag="trinidad">
			<flagMeaning>The red is said to represent the vitality of the land and people, the warmth and energy of the sun, and courage and friendliness; the white is said to represent the sea, the purity of national aspirations, and the equality of all men; and the black to represent strength, unity and purpose, and the natural resources.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Trinidad and Tobago are twin islands located in the Caribbean sea (South East of the North American continent). Trinidad was sighted in 1498 by Columbus, who christened it La Isla de la Trinidad, for the Holy Trinity. The Spanish who followed in Columbus' wake enslaved many of Trinidad's Amerindian inhabitants, taking them to toil in the new South American colonies. Over the next two centuries unsuccessful attempts were made by Spanish colonisers to establish tobacco and cacao plantations but crop failures and a lack of support from Spain left the island only slightly settled. As a result, the British took the islands from the Spanish in 1797. Tobago was also sighted by Columbus and claimed by the Spanish but there were no attempts to colonise it. During the 17th century, Tobago changed hands numerous times as the English, French, Dutch and even Courlanders (present-day Latvians!) wrestled for control. The British returned to establish a colonial administration on Tobago in 1763, and within two decades 10,000 African slaves were imported to establish the island's sugar, cotton and indigo plantations. Tobago's plantation economy slid into decline after the abolition of slavery but sugar and rum production continued until 1884. Following WWI demands for autonomy grew and in 1962, independence was eventually granted. Trinidad and Tobago is one of the most prosperous countries in the Caribbean, thanks largely to petroleum and natural gas production and processing. Tourism, mostly in Tobago, is targeted for expansion and is growing. </history>
			<historyClue>Sighted in 1498 by Columbus, the next two centuries proved unsuccessful for the Spanish colonisers in their attempts to establish tobacco and cacao plantations. Crop failures and a lack of support from Spain left the island only slightly settled, and as a result, the British took the islands from the Spanish in 1797.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>These islands sit between the Caribbean Sea and the North Atlantic Ocean</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="United States" capital="Washington, DC" flag="usB">
			<flagMeaning>The red and white are the national colours of the United States. The 50 stars correspond to the 50 states of the country. The flag might be changed soon to show 51 stars for 50 states and one district (Columbia).</flagMeaning>
			<history>It is believed that the continent's first inhabitants walked into North America across what is now the Bering Strait from Asia. For the next 20,000 years these pioneering settlers were essentially left alone to develop distinct and dynamic cultures. In the modern US, their descendants include the Pueblo people in what is now New Mexico; Apache in Texas; Navajo in Arizona, Colorado and Utah; Hopi in Arizona; Crow in Montana; Cherokee in North Carolina; and Mohawk and Iroquois in New York State. The Norwegian explorer Leif Eriksson was the first European to reach North America. By the mid-1550s, much of the Americas had been poked and prodded by a cavalcade of explorers from Spain, Portugal, England and France. The first colonies attracted immigrants looking to get rich quickly and return home, but they were soon followed by migrants whose primary goal was to colonise. Britain's American colonies broke with the mother country in 1776 and were recognised as the new nation of the United States of America following the Treaty of Paris in 1783. During the 19th and 20th centuries, 37 new states were added to the original 13 as the nation expanded across the North American continent and acquired a number of overseas possessions. The two most traumatic experiences in the nation's history were the Civil War (1861-65) and the Great Depression of the 1930s. This has to be contrasted by victories in World Wars I and II and the end of the Cold War in 1991. The US remains the world's most powerful nation-state.</history>
			<historyClue>The two most traumatic experiences in the nation's history were the Civil War (1861-65) and the Great Depression of the 1930s. This has to be contrasted by victories in World Wars I and II and the end of the Cold War in 1991.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Mexico</geoClue>
		</country>
	</continent>

	<continent name="South America">
		<country name="Argentina" capital="Buenos Aires" flag="argentinaB">
			<flagMeaning>The colours of the flag personify the sky, the clouds, the sea and the sun. The sun takes its origin from  the Inca culture. Viracocha is the god creator; Inti is the Sun. Inti is the son of Viracocha. Viracocha is the Sun God. Inti is the astronomical object; the Sun. Incas depict Viracocha as a man, and Inti in the shape of a disc, with a face on it and flaming rays around it. It is also represented square, as in Tiahuanacu, with no torso but with legs and arms. (As if merging Viracocha and Inti, which are two: one created by the other.)</flagMeaning>
			<history>Argentina is located on the South East part of South America and is the second largest country in South America (after Brazil). Pre-Columbian Argentina was farmed by sedentary Indian groups such as the Diaguita and used as a hunting ground by nomads. Indian resistance kept Spanish invasions at bay and Buenos Aires was not successfully established until 1580. A declining and unevenly distributed Indian population, which could not be enslaved, led to the creation of huge cattle ranches, known as haciendas - the birth of the legendary gaucho (cowboy) and the source of great wealth for a lucky few. In 1816, Argentina gained independence. With the new Unitarist constitution of 1853, a new era of growth and prosperity reigned until excessive foreign interests made the Argentinian economy vulnerable and the first decades of the 20th century saw increasingly weak civilian rule, economic failure, continuing resentment of the landed elite and distrust of British interests, leading to a military coup in 1943 which paved the way for the rise of dictator Juan Perón. After Perón's death, Argentina experienced increasing economic problems  and political instability and kidnappings, guerilla warfare, with the new military government instituting a reign of terror from 1976-1983, a period described as the years of Dirty War. 2003 saw democracy return and Argentina is now facing a long and arduous climb out of its prolonged recession.</history>
			<historyClue>After Perón's death, this country experienced increasing economic problems  and political instability and kidnappings, guerilla warfare, with the new military government instituting a reign of terror from 1976-1983, a period described as the years of Dirty War.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Chile</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Brazil" capital="Brasilia" flag="brazilB">
			<flagMeaning>According to Felipe Flores Pinto, the colours green and yellow refer to the Royal Houses of Braganca (Emperor Pedro I) and Habsburg (Empress Leopoldina). The blue sphere is a portrait of the sky of Rio de Janeiro on the night of 15 November 1889. According to some unofficial sources, on 7 September 1822, after demanding "Independence or Death," Prince Regent Pedro (later Emperor Dom Pedro I) removed the Portuguese blue-and-white cockade from his hat and exclaimed, "From now on we will have another ribbon-knot ('laco'), green and yellow. These will be the national colours." On 18 September, Pedro signed three decrees that were the first acts of independent Brazil. The second decree created a new national cockade: "The Brazilian national bow-knot (laco), or cockade (tope) will be composed of the emblematic colours: green for spring and yellow for gold....". The stars, as stated before represent the view of the sky from Rio de Janeiro on the 15 November 1889. There are as many stars on the flag as they are states in Brazil. The white band crossing the blue sphere has the following inscription on it: " Order and Progress", which is attributed to the French positivist philosopher Auguste Comte, who had many followers in Brazil, including Professor Teixeira Mendes, who conceived the basic design of the flag.  
</flagMeaning>
			<history>In contrast to the Inca and Maya, the Brazilian Indians never developed a centralised civilisation. In 1500 Pedro Alvares Cabral set sail from Lisbon with 13 ships and 1200 crew, ostensibly for India, and arrived on the Brazilian coast near present-day Porto Seguro by 'accident'. In 1531 King João III of Portugal sent the first settlers to Brazil and, in 1534, fearing the ambitions of other European countries, he divided the coast into 15 hereditary captaincies, which were given to friends of the Crown. After being under the rule of Portugal for decades, Brazil gained its independence in 1822. For most of the 19th and 20th centuries, Brazil suffered economic depression, military governance, and political corruption until in November 1989, Brazilians had their first opportunity to elect a president by popular vote in almost 30 years. By 2000 the economy was growing again but gains in education, land reform and welfare compete against a ailing health system, urban overcrowding, rural landlessness and environmental abuse. Corruption in Brazil remains a way of life, despite the beginnings of attempts to tackle it and highly unequal income distribution remains a pressing problem. With an estimated 170 million inhabitants, Brazil has the largest population in Latin America and ranks sixth in the world.</history>
			<historyClue>In 1531 King João III of Portugal sent the first settlers to this country and, in 1534, fearing the ambitions of other European countries, he divided the coast into 15 hereditary captaincies, which were given to friends of the Crown. After being under the rule of Portugal for decades, it gained its independence in 1822.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Venezuela</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Chile" capital="Santiago" flag="chileB">
			<flagMeaning>According to some unofficial sources, the Chilean flag was designed by an American named Charles Wood, while serving as a volunteer in the Chilean Army. The flag was adopted in 1817. The design was probably influenced by the American flag. The white stands for the snow of the Andes Mountains; the blue is symbolic of the sky and the red represents the sacrifices of the people. The white star is an ancient Indian (American Indian) symbol meaning honour, and it is thought that the five points of the star represents the five original provinces of the country.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Chile is located on the South West side of South America. Pre-Columbian Chile was peopled by a variety of ancient cultures, predating the Incas by many centuries. All territory west of Brazil was granted to Spain by the 1494 Spanish-Portuguese treaty. The Spanish assigned the task of conquering Chile to Pedro de Valdivia, whose expedition reached Chile's fertile Mapocho Valley in 1541. The native population was all but annihilated by the unwitting introduction of infectious diseases, and the mestizo population - the offspring of Spanish and Indian unions - were used as tenant laborers on these huge estates. In 1810 Simón Bolívar and José de San Martín led armies of freedom fighters from Venezuela to Peru, and from Argentina into Chile and on 12 February 1818 independence was formally declared. On 11 September 1973, General Pinochet seized power in a bloody coup and dark days followed, with assassinations, purges and enforced exiles commonplace. It is estimated that as many as 80,000 people were tortured or murdered. Finally, with the 1989 multiparty elections, democracy returned to Chile and the introduction of economic reforms helped alleviate crushing poverty to some degree.</history>
			<historyClue> In 1810 Simón Bolívar and José de San Martín led armies of freedom fighters and on 12 February 1818 independence was formally declared. On 11 September 1973, General Pinochet seized power in a bloody coup and dark days followed, with assassinations, purges and enforced exiles commonplace. </historyClue>
			<geoClue>Bolivia</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Colombia" capital="Bogota" flag="colombiaB">
			<flagMeaning>Although this is not an official source, a very popular Colombian song that children chant is as follow: "YELLOW is our gold, BLUE is our vast seas (oceans) and RED is the blood that gave us our freedom... (from Spain)". Another source would see the yellow symbolising sovereignty and justice; the blue nobility, loyalty and vigilance; and the red valour, honour, generosity and victory achieved at the high cost of bloodshed.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Colombia is located on the North of South America. In 1499, Alonso de Ojeda, a companion of Christopher Columbus, landed on the Guajira Peninsula. Soon, a large part of what became Colombia had been conquered by the Spanish, and a number of towns, including Cartagena (founded in 1533), were prospering. In 1544, the country was incorporated into the viceroyalty of Peru, where it remained until 1739 when it became a part of New Granada (comprising the territories of what are today Colombia, Venezuela, Ecuador and Panama). Soon, a large part of what became Colombia had been conquered by the Spanish, and a number of towns, including Cartagena (founded in 1533), were prospering. In 1544, the country was incorporated into the viceroyalty of Peru, where it remained until 1739 when it became a part of New Granada (comprising the territories of what are today Colombia, Venezuela, Ecuador and Panama). Towards the end of the 18th century, the first stirrings of national autonomy started to emerge, but it wasn't until 1819, and the appearance of Venezuelan liberator Simon Bolívar and his army, that independence was achieved. Ten years of uneasy confederation with Venezuela and Ecuador followed in the form of Gran Colombia, until regional differences between the three finally undermined the union resulting in Gran Colombia dissolving into three separate countries. In the course of the 19th century, the country experienced no less than eight civil wars, culminating in the bloody War of a Thousand Days in 1899. In 1948 after a period of relative peace, Colombia's most cruel and destructive of Colombia's many civil wars broke out  with La Violencia. Close to 300,000 died in the conflict. By 1990, escalating violence (increasingly leveled at members of the ruling political class) threatened to bring the country to a standstill. A new constitution came into effect in 1991 which provided greater judicial powers and strengthened government control. However, drug trafficking continues to grow (courtesy of the pragmatic Cali cartel), bringing in an estimated US$6 billion a year. </history>
			<historyClue>By 1990, escalating violence (increasingly leveled at members of the ruling political class) threatened to bring this country to a standstill. A new constitution came into effect in 1991 which provided greater judicial powers and strengthened government control. However, drug trafficking continues to grow (courtesy of the pragmatic Cali cartel), bringing in an estimated US$6 billion a year. </historyClue>
			<geoClue>Panama</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Guyana" capital="Georgetown" flag="guyanaB">
			<flagMeaning>The Golden Arrowhead - Guyana's national flag - has 5 symbolic colours: green for the agricultural and forested nature of Guyana; white for the river and water potential of the country, black for the endurance that will sustain the forward thrust of the Guyana's people, and red for the zeal and dynamic nature of nation-building which lies before the young and independent Guyana. The GOLDEN arrow represents Guyana's mineral wealth,</flagMeaning>
			<history>Guyana is located on the North West of South America. It is the third smallest country in South America (after Suriname and Uruguay). The aboriginal inhabitants of the Guyanese coast were Carib Indians who had driven the peaceful Arawak north and westwards into the Antilles. European settlement didn't occur until 1615, when the Dutch West Indian Company erected a fort and depot on the lower Essequibo River. The Dutch traded with the Indian peoples of the interior, and established riverside plantations - worked by African slaves - and sugar quickly became the dominant crop. From 1846-1917, almost 250,000 laborers entered Guyana, dramatically transforming the country's demographic balance and laying the basis for persistent ethnic tensions. Guyana achieved independence in 1966 and four years later became a cooperative republic within the Commonwealth, but until the early 1990s it was ruled mostly by socialist-oriented governments. In 1992, Cheddi JAGAN was elected president in what is considered the country's first free and fair election since independence.</history>
			<historyClue>European settlement didn't occur until 1615, when the Dutch West Indian Company erected a fort and depot on the lower Essequibo River.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Venezuela</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Bolivia" capital="La Paz / Sucre" flag="boliviaB">
			<flagMeaning>The green signifies the fertility of the country, the red represents valour (probably the valour of Bolivia's past heroes) and the yellow stands for the richness of the natural resources of the country.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Bolivia is located in the centre of South America, completely surrounded by land. It has two capitals: La Paz (seat of government) and Sucre (which is the legal capital and seat of judiciary).Civilisation in the Bolivian Andes is thought to stretch back some 21,000 years. The most influential Pre-Columbian cultures were the Tiahuanaco, who were based around Lake Titicaca and who ruled the region between AD 600-1200, and the Incas, who headed a vast empire comprising most of Peru, Bolivia, Ecuador and northern Chile. The Spanish conquest of the country began in 1531 under Francisco Pizarro. The conquistadors made rapid progress, exploiting the trust (and later the disunity) of the Indians to secure the territory that within two years became known as Alto Peru. Struggle for independence began in 1809, but it remained part of Spain until 1825, when it was liberated by Simón Bolívar, for whom the nation was later named. After briefly being part of a union with Peru, Bolivia became fully independent. In following years, Bolivia lost a lot of ground through war and sales. Faced with racial and cultural troubles, Bolivia has recorded nearly 200 coups and counter coups: revolution and military. A military junta was overthrown in the early 1980s to reinstate democracy, but leaders have since (and still) faced difficult problems of deep-seated poverty, social unrest, and drug production.</history>
			<historyClue>Struggle for independence began in 1809, but it remained part of Spain until 1825, when it was liberated by Simón Bolívar, for whom the nation was later named.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Peru</geoClue>
		</country>
		<country name="Peru" capital="Lima" flag="peruB">
			<flagMeaning>To date, no clear account defining the symbolism of the Peruvian flag seems to have been proffered. However, there seems to be an unspoken universal agreement that the red stands for "thousands of heroes" who fell for the country.</flagMeaning>
			<history>Peru is located on the West part of South America. The first inhabitants of Peru were nomadic hunter-gatherers who lived in caves in Peru's coastal regions. The oldest site, Pikimachay cave, dates from 12,000 BC. By the early 15th century, the Inca empire had control of much of the area, even extending its influence into Colombia and Chile. Between 1526-28, the Spanish conquistador Francisco Pizarro explored Peru's coastal regions and, drawn by the riches of the Inca empire, returned to Spain to raise and recruit men for another expedition to the country. Pizarro subsequently founded the city of Lima in 1535 but was assassinated six years later. The next 200 years proved peaceful, with Lima becoming the major political, social and commercial center of the Andean nations. However, the exploitation of Indians by their colonial masters led to an uprising in 1780 under the self-styled Inca Tupac Amaru II. The rebellion was shortlived and most of the leaders were rounded up and executed. Peru continued to remain loyal to Spain until 1824, when the country was liberated by two 'outsiders': the Venezuelan Simón Bolívar and the Argentinian José de San Martín. After a dozen years of military rule, Peru returned to democratic leadership in 1980, but experienced economic problems and the growth of a violent insurgency. President Alberto FUJIMORI's election in 1990 ushered in a decade that saw a dramatic turnaround in the economy and significant progress in curtailing guerrilla activity. In the April 2000 elections, Alejandro Toledo, an Andean Indian from a poor family who became a World Bank economist, won a tight race and in June 2001 became the country's first indigenous president.</history>
			<historyClue>Between 1526-28, the Spanish conquistador Francisco Pizarro explored this country's coastal regions and, drawn by the riches of the Inca empire, returned to Spain to raise and recruit men for another expedition to the country. Pizarro subsequently founded the city of Lima in 1535.</historyClue>
			<geoClue>Ecuador</geoClue>
		</country>
	</continent>
</world>
